A Guide to the Joseph C. McDaniel Papers
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10553-aa
Joseph C. McDaniel Papers ca. 1949-1981, n.d.
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10553-aa
ca. 2000 items
Mary Nell McDonald
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the University of Virginia Library by Mary Nell McDaniel, Urbana, Illinois, on November 17, 1994.
Scope and Content
This addition to the Joseph C. McDaniel Papers, ca. 1949-1981, and undated, ca. 2,000 items (6 Hollinger boxes, ca. 2.5 linear shelf feet), includes his professional correspondence at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign; handwritten and typed articles about persimmons, magnolias, and other plants; notebooks containing field notes and pollination records and notes concerning other plant research; material pertaining to his membership in the American Magnolia Society, including reports, articles, and correspondence; and printed material.
Container List
- Series I: Articles
  - American Magnolia Society, 1970-1981, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 1)
  - Bamboos, n.d. (Box Box 1)
  - Buckeyes & Horse Chestnuts, 1961-1972 (Box Box 1)
  - Cacti (includes notes), 1969-1974, n.d. (Box Box 1)
  - Hollies, 1972-1974, n.d. (Box Box 1)
  - Hydrangeas, 1966, n.d. (Box Box 1)
  - Magnolias, 1963-1981; (4 folders) (Box Box 1)
  - Magnolias (includes notes) - Incomplete, 1965-1977, n.d.; (3 folders) (Box Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Fruit, 1964-1970, n.d. (Box Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Trees, 1965-1976, n.d. (Box Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous - Incomplete, 1977, n.d. (Box Box 2)
  - Papaws (includes notes), 1968-1971, n.d. (Box Box 2)
  - Pecans and Other Nut Trees, 1951-1978, n.d. (Box Box 3)
  - Persimmons, 1970-1978, n.d. (Box Box 3)
  - Redbuds, n.d. (Box Box 3)
  - Rhodora - Incomplete, 1957, n.d. (Box Box 3)
  - Serviceberries, n.d. (Box Box 3)
  - Yuccas, 1970-1975 (Box Box 3)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1949-1969; (7 folders) (Box Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1975 May; (8 folders) (Box Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1975 Jun-1981, n.d.; (9 folders) (Box Box 5)
- Series III: Miscellaneous Papers
  - American Magnolia Society Papers, 1961-1980, n.d. (Box Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1968-1980, n.d. (Box Box 6)
  - Notes, 1964-1975 (Box Box 6)
  - Photographs, n.d. (Box Box 6)
  - Pollination Records & Field Notes [25 Notebooks], 1953-1980, n.d.; (4 folders) (Box Box 6)
  - Bound Volume of Field Notes, Yu-Chen Ting Trip Fund, and Pollinations, 1963, 1976 (Box Box 6)
  - Bibliographical Listing (Magnolia Checklist), 1975 (Box Oversize Folder)